A Guide to the Papers of the Norfolk Forum, 1930-
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Speakers 1942-2005
  - Forum Speakers 1942-2003
    - Adler, Mortimer -- News Clippings January 1985 (Box-folder 11:8)
    - Agar, Herbert -- Introduction 6 April 1948 (Box-folder 11:9)
    - Albright, Madeline -- News Clippings October 2001 (Box-folder 11:10)
    - Allen, Joy -- Introduction 11 February 1942 (Box-folder 11:11)
    - Anderson, Jack -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:12)
    - Anderson, Jack -- Business and Correspondence 1981-1982 (Box-folder 11:13)
    - Annison, Michael -- News Clippings December 1983 (Box-folder 11:14)
    - Bailey, Pearl -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:15)
    - Bailey, Pearl -- Introduction 20 October 1987 (Box-folder 11:16)
    - Bailey, Pearl -- News Clippings October 1987 (Box-folder 11:17)
    - Ballard, Robert D. -- News Clippings May 2003 (Box-folder 11:18)
    - Barak, Ehud -- News Clippings October 2002 (Box-folder 11:19)
    - Bloomberg, Michael -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:20)
    - Bork, Robert -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:21)
    - Bork, Robert -- Business and Correspondence 1992 (Box-folder 11:22)
    - Bork, Robert -- News Clippings November 1992 (Box-folder 11:23)
    - Bradlee, Ben -- Introduction 11 February 1998 (Box-folder 11:24)
    - Brady, Ray -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:25)
    - Breashears, David -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:26)
    - Breashears, David -- Business and Correspondence 1998-1999 (Box-folder 11:27)
    - Breashears, David -- Introduction 11 May 1999 (Box-folder 11:28)
    - Britt, L. -- Biography undated (Box-folder 11:29)
    - Brokaw, Tom -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:30)
    - Brokaw, Tom -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:30)
    - Brokaw, Tom -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 11:30)
    - Brokaw, Tom -- Business and Correspondence 1991-1992 (Box-folder 11:31)
    - Brokaw, Tom -- News Clippings January 1993 (Box-folder 11:32)
    - Brzezinski, Zbgniew -- Introduction 18 September 1990 (Box-folder 11:33)
    - Brzezinski, Zbgniew -- News Clippings September 1990 (Box-folder 11:34)
    - Burger, Warren -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 12:1)
    - Burger, Warren -- Business and Correspondence 1987 (Box-folder 12:2)
    - Burger, Warren -- News Clippings November 1987 (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Burns, Ken -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Burns, Ken -- Business and Correspondence 1995 (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Burns, Ken -- Introduction 27 February 1996 (Box-folder 12:6)
    - Burns, Ken -- News Clippings February 1996 (Box-folder 12:7)
    - Bush, George -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 12:8)
    - Bush, George -- Business and Correspondence 1993-1994 (Box-folder 12:9)
    - Bush, George -- News Clippings February 1994 (Box-folder 12:10)
    - The Capital Steps -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 12:11)
    - The Capital Steps -- Business and Correspondence 1992 (Box-folder 12:12)
    - The Capital Steps -- Introduction 29 September 1992 (Box-folder 12:13)
    - Cheney, Dick -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 12:14)
    - Cheney, Dick -- Business and Correspondence 1993 (Box-folder 12:15)
    - Compton, Ann -- News Clippings November 1984 (Box-folder 12:16)
    - Cuomo, Mario -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 12:17)
    - Cuomo, Mario -- Business and Correspondence 1992-1993 (Box-folder 12:18)
    - Cuomo, Mario -- News Clippings October 1993 (Box-folder 12:19)
    - De Klerk, F.W. -- Business and Correspondence 1999 (Box-folder 12:20)
    - Dole, Bob -- Business and Correspondence 1997 (Box-folder 12:21)
    - Dole, Bob -- News Clippings November 1997 (Box-folder 12:22)
    - Dole, Elizabeth -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 12:23)
    - Dole, Elizabeth -- Business and Correspondence 1998 (Box-folder 12:24)
    - Dole, Elizabeth -- Introduction 1 October 1998 (Box-folder 12:25)
    - Dole, Elizabeth -- News Clippings October 1998 (Box-folder 12:26)
    - Ervin, Sam J. -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Ervin, Sam J. -- Business and Correspondence 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13:2)
    - Fallows, James -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Ervin, Sam J. -- Business and Correspondence 1996-1997 (Box-folder 13:4)
    - Fallows, James, Kevin Phillips, and Charlie Rose -- News Clippings February 1997 (Box-folder 13:5)
    - Ford, President Gerald -- Business and Correspondence 1989 (Box-folder 13:6)
    - Ford, President Gerald -- Introduction September 20, 1989 (Box-folder 13:7)
    - Ford, President Gerald -- News Clippings September 1989 (Box-folder 13:8)
    - Friedman, Thomas -- News Clippings January 2005 (Box-folder 13:9)
    - Goodall, Jane -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:10)
    - Goodall, Jane -- Business and Correspondence 1996-1997 (Box-folder 13:11)
    - Goodall, Jane -- Introduction 1 April 1997 (Box-folder 13:12)
    - Goodall, Jane -- News Clippings April 1997 (Box-folder 13:13)
    - Goodall, Jane -- Jane Goodall Institute undated (Box-folder 13:14)
    - Goodwin, Doris K. -- News Clippings May 2002 (Box-folder 13:15)
    - Goodman, Ellen -- Introduction 9 October 1990 (Box-folder 13:16)
    - Gore, Al -- News Clippings January 2004 (Box-folder 13:17)
    - Graham, Senator Frank Porter -- Introduction 6 December 1949 (Box-folder 13:18)
    - Grasso, Richard -- News Clippings October 2003 (Box-folder 13:19)
    - Jarvis, Dr. Charles -- Business and Correspondence 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13:20)
    - King, Coretta Scott -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:21)
    - King, Coretta Scott -- Business and Correspondence 1981-1982 (Box-folder 13:22)
    - King, Larry -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:23)
    - Kirkpatrick, Dr. Jeane -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:24)
    - Kirkpatrick, Dr. Jeane -- Business and Correspondence 1992-1994 (Box-folder 13:25)
    - Kirkpatrick, Dr. Jeane -- News Clippings May 1994 (Box-folder 13:26)
    - Kissenger, Henry -- Business and Correspondence 1991 (Box-folder 13:27)
    - Kissenger, Henry -- Introduction 30 September 1991 (Box-folder 13:28)
    - Kissenger, Henry -- News Clippings 1991 (Box-folder 13:29)
    - Knop, Werner -- Introduction 9 December 1952 (Box-folder 13:30)
    - Koch, Ed -- Introduction 5 February 1991 (Box-folder 13:31)
    - Koch, Ed -- News Clippings February 1991 (Box-folder 13:32)
    - Koop, C. Everette -- Introduction 16 April 1991 (Box-folder 13:33)
    - Koop, C. Everette -- Business and Correspondence 1991 (Box-folder 13:34)
    - Koop, C. Everette - News Clippings April-May 1991 (Box-folder 13:35)
    - Krzyzewski, Mike -- News Clippings 2003 (Box-folder 13:36)
    - Landers, Ann -- Business and Correspondence 1991 (Box-folder 13:37)
    - Lewis, Anthony -- News Clippings January 1984 (Box-folder 13:38)
    - Lynch, Peter -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:39)
    - Lynch, Peter -- Business and Correspondence 1995 (Box-folder 13:40)
    - Lynch, Peter -- Introduction 7 November 1995 (Box-folder 13:41)
    - Lynch, Peter -- News Clippings November 1995 (Box-folder 13:42)
    - MacNeil, Robert -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:43)
    - MacNeil, Robert -- Business and Correspondence 1993-1994 (Box-folder 13:44)
    - MacNeil, Robert -- News Clippings 1994 (Box-folder 13:45)
    - Major, John -- Business and Correspondence 1997 (Box-folder 13:46)
    - Major, John -- Introduction 15 October 1997 (Box-folder 13:47)
    - Major, John -- News Clippings October 1997 (Box-folder 13:48)
    - Martin, Judith (Miss Manners) -- News Clippings March 2002 (Box-folder 13:49)
    - McCullough, David -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:50)
    - McCullough, David -- News Clippings April 2005 (Box-folder 13:51)
    - McDowell, Charles -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:52)
    - Middleton, Drew -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 13:53)
    - McDowell, Charles -- Business and Correspondence 1982 (Box-folder 13:54)
    - Moyers, Bill -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:1)
    - Moyers, Bill -- Business and Correspondence 1986 (Box-folder 14:2)
    - Moyers, Bill -- News Clippings November 1986 (Box-folder 14:3)
    - Mulroney, Brian -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:4)
    - Mulroney, Brian -- Business and Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box-folder 14:5)
    - Mulroney, Brian -- Introduction 19 September 1995 (Box-folder 14:6)
    - Mulroney, Brian -- News Clippings September 1995 (Box-folder 14:7)
    - Nader, Ralph -- News Clippings October 1970 (Box-folder 14:8)
    - O'Neill, Jr., Thomas P. -- Business and Correspondence 1990 (Box-folder 14:9)
    - O'Neill, Jr., Thomas P. -- Introductiom 17 April 1990 (Box-folder 14:10)
    - Osgood, Charles -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:11)
    - Osgood, Charles -- Introduction 21 October 1980 (Box-folder 14:12)
    - Osgood, Charles -- News Clippings 1980 (Box-folder 14:13)
    - Page, Clarence -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:14)
    - Page, Clarence -- Business and Correspondence 1992 (Box-folder 14:15)
    - Phillips, Kevin -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:16)
    - Phillips, Kevin -- Business and Correspondence 1996 (Box-folder 14:17)
    - Pierpoint, Robert -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:18)
    - Pierpoint, Robert -- Business and Correspondence 1982 (Box-folder 14:19)
    - Pierpoint, Robert -- News Clippings October 1992 (Box-folder 14:20)
    - Powell, Colin -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:21)
    - Powell, Colin -- Business and Correspondence 1992-1994 (Box-folder 14:22)
    - Powell, Colin -- News Clippings September 1994 (Box-folder 14:23)
    - Powell, Judy -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:24)
    - Raman, T.A. -- Business and Correspondence 1944 (Box-folder 14:25)
    - Rather, Dan -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:26)
    - Rather, Dan -- Business and Correspondence 1997-1998 (Box-folder 14:27)
    - Rather, Dan -- Introduction 8 November 1998 (Box-folder 14:28)
    - Reich, Robert -- News Clippings October 2003 (Box-folder 14:29)
    - Roberts, Cokie -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:30)
    - Roberts, Cokie -- Business and Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box-folder 14:31)
    - Roberts, Cokie -- Introduction 2 April 1996 (Box-folder 14:32)
    - Roberts, Cokie -- News Clippings April 1996 (Box-folder 14:33)
    - Rose, Charlie -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:34)
    - Rose, Charlie -- Business and Correspondence 1996-1997 (Box-folder 14:35)
    - Rowan, Carl -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:36)
    - Roberts, Cokie -- News Clippings February 1987 (Box-folder 14:37)
    - Russell, Mark -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:38)
    - Russell, Mark -- Business and Correspondence 1982-1983, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 14:39)
    - Russell, Mark -- Introduction 19 November 1996 (Box-folder 14:40)
    - Russell, Mark -- News Clippings November 1996 (Box-folder 14:41)
    - Schneider, William -- Business and Correspondence 1997 (Box-folder 14:42)
    - Siskel, Gene and Roger Ebert -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 14:43)
    - Siskel, Gene and Roger Ebert -- Business and Correspondence 1992-1993 (Box-folder 14:44)
    - Siskel, Gene and Roger Ebert -- News Clippings December 1993 (Box-folder 14:45)
    - Steinbrenner, George -- Business and Correspondence 1993-1995 (Box-folder 15:1)
    - Steinbrenner, George -- News Clippings January 1995 (Box-folder 15:2)
    - Thatcher, Margaret -- Business and Correspondence 1991-1992 (Box-folder 15:3)
    - Thatcher, Margaret -- News Clippings April 1992 (Box-folder 15:4)
    - Trudeau, Gary -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 15:5)
    - Trudeau, Gary -- Business and Correspondence 1998-1999 (Box-folder 15:6)
    - Trudeau, Gary -- Introduction 23 February 1999 (Box-folder 15:7)
    - TuTu, Desmond Archbishop -- Business and Correspondence 1996-1997 (Box-folder 15:8)
    - Ueberroth, Peter -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 15:9)
    - Ueberroth, Peter -- Business and Correspondence 1993-1994 (Box-folder 15:10)
    - Ueberroth, Peter -- News Clippings April 1994 (Box-folder 15:11)
    - Van Buren, Abigail -- Introduction 13 January 1981 (Box-folder 15:12)
    - Walters, Barbara -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 15:13)
    - Walters, Barbara -- Business and Correspondence 1992-1996 (Box-folder 15:14)
    - Walters, Barbara -- News Clippings September-October 1996 (Box-folder 15:15)
    - Walters, Barbara -- Introduction 2 October 1996 (Box-folder 15:16)
    - Watts, J.C. -- News Clippings 2004 (Box-folder 15:17)
    - Will, George F. -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 15:18)
    - Will, George F. -- News Clippings March 1989 (Box-folder 15:19)
    - Williams, Junius H. -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 15:20)
    - Wolfe, Tom -- Biography and Background undated (Box-folder 15:21)
    - Wolfe, Tom -- Business and Correspondence 1982-1986 (Box-folder 15:22)
    - Wolfe, Tom -- News Clippings 1986 (Box-folder 15:23)
    - Introductions -- Miscellaneous undated (Box-folder 15:24)
    - Speaker Biographies -- Miscellaneous undated (Box-folder 15:25)
  - Prospective Speakers 1980-2000
    This sub-series contains information and correspondence related to prospective speakers that did not actually speak before the Norfolk Forum, speaker recommendations, and rejection letters from prospective speakers.
    Alphabetical by speaker's last name and subject heading
    - Carter, Stephen 1995 (Box-folder 15:26)
    - de Klerk, F.W. 1996 (Box-folder 15:27)
    - Gumbel, Bryant 1992 (Box-folder 15:28)
    - Rainer, Prince 1993-1994 (Box-folder 15:29)
    - Richards, Anne 1993-1994 (Box-folder 15:30)
    - Rukeyser, Louis 1994 (Box-folder 15:31)
    - Seinfield, Jerry 1997 (Box-folder 15:32)
    - Speaker Recommendations 1980-1990 (Box-folder 15:33)
    - Speaker Recommendations 1990-2000 (Box-folder 15:34)
    - Speaker Rejections 1986-1998 (Box-folder 15:35)
  - Speaker Agencies
    This sub-series contains information related to various speaker agencies including promotional material for the agencies and their speakers, and correspondence between the Norfolk Forum and these agencies.
    Alphabetical by agency name
    - Capital Speakers (Box-folder 16:1)
    - Cassidy and Fishman (Box-folder 16:2)
    - CC & L Speakers Group (Box-folder 16:3)
    - The Fischer Ross Group (Box-folder 16:4)
    - Greater Talent Network (Box-folder 16:5)
    - Henry Walker Agency (Box-folder 16:6)
    - ICM Artists (Box-folder 16:7)
    - The Jerome Group (Box-folder 16:8)
    - Johnson and Company (Box-folder 16:9)
    - K & S Speakers (Box-folder 16:10)
    - The Kendig Speaker's Network (Box-folder 16:11)
    - Keppler Associates (Box-folder 16:12)
    - Leigh Bureau (Box-folder 16:13)
    - Pacific Mountain Network (Box-folder 16:14)
    - Potomac Speakers Bureau (Box-folder 16:15)
    - Ross Associates Speakers Bureau (Box-folder 16:16)
    - Royce Carlton (Box-folder 17:1)
    - Ruth Alban Speakers Service (Box-folder 17:2)
    - Shelia Grant's International Celebrity Network (Box-folder 17:3)
    - Speakers Guild (Box-folder 17:4)
    - Washington Speakers Bureau (Box-folder 17:5)
    - W. Colston Leigh, Inc. (Box-folder 17:6)
    - William Morris Agency (Box-folder 17:7)
    - Speaker Agencies -- Miscellaneous (Box-folder 17:8)
- Other Organizations undated, 1935, 1939-1950, 1979-1998
  This series contains three sub-series including information on other organizations and corporations.
  - Affiliated Organizations 1990, 1993-1998
    This sub-series contains information about organizations associated with the Norfolk Forum, such as the Bruce Shafer World Peace Trust and the Foodbank of Southeastern Virginia.
    Alphabetical by organization name
    - The Bruce Shafer World Peace Trust 1993-1998 (Box-folder 17:9)
    - The Foodbank of Southeastern Virginia 1990 (Box-folder 17:10)
  - Other Forums 1939, 1945-1946, 1979-1983, 1993-1996
    This sub-series contains information about other forums and lecture series similar to the Norfolk Forum.
    - Portsmouth Forum undated, 1939, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 17:11)
    - Richmond Forum 1994-1996 (Box-folder 17:12)
    - Town Hall of Cleveland Lecture Series 1979-1983 (Box-folder 17:13)
    - Virginia Beach Forum 1996 (Box-folder 17:14)
    - World Affairs Council of Greater Hampton Roads 1993-1994 (Box-folder 17:15)
    - Miscellaneous Forums undated (Box-folder 17:16)
  - Services and Leasing Agencies undated, 1935, 1940-1950, 1982-1997
    This sub-series contains information related to various businesses and agencies that the Norfolk Forum has done business with, specifically the leasing of space for events and receptions, and making arrangements for speaker transportation and accommodations.
    - Blair Junior High School Auditorium 1935 (Box-folder 17:17)
    - Center Theater 1940-1950 (Box-folder 17:18)
    - Harbor Club 1993-1994 (Box-folder 17:19)
    - Omni Hotel 1993-1995 (Box-folder 17:20)
    - Scope and Chrysler Hall 1982-1997 (Box-folder 17:21)
    - Miscellaneous Services and Leasing Contacts undated (Box-folder 17:22)
    - Miscellaneous Oversize Photographs (from Series VIII, See Box 32) undated (Box-folder 17:23)
- Multimedia undated, 1997-2005
  This series contains audiotapes and videotapes of Norfolk Forum Oral Histories and selected speaker appearances.
  Chronological by the date of the interview or event
  - Audiocassettes undated, 1997
    This sub-series contains mini-audiocassettes of the Norfolk Forum Oral History Project. This was conducted in 1997 by the Norfolk Forum with the assistance of Mr. Paul Chandler Moulton, a local historian and teaching assistant at ODU, as part of the Norfolk Forum's History Project.
    - Index Cards containing questions, 45 qty (Box-folder 18:1)
    - Dr. Wilcox Ruffin 6 June 1997, Mini-audiocassette (Box-folder 18:2)
    - Carter Scott 26 July 1997, Mini-audiocassette (Box-folder 18:3)
    - E.L. Ryan, Sr. 30 July 1997, Mini-audiocassette (Box-folder 18:4)
    - John Ryan 1 August 1997, Mini-audiocassette -- 2 qty (Box-folder 18:5)
    - Allen Donn 12 August 1997, Mini-audiocassette (Box-folder 18:6)
    - Glenn Scott undated, Mini-audiocassette (Box-folder 18:7)
    - Not Labeled undated, Mini-audiocassettes -- 5 qty (Box-folder 18:8)
  - Videocassettes 2000-2001
    This sub-series contains VHS tapes of various speakers.
    - James Lovell 12 December 2000, Beta videotape -- (1 of 3) (Box-folder 19:1)
    - James Lovell 12 December 2000, Beta videotape -- (2 of 3) (Box-folder 19:2)
    - James Lovell 12 December 2000, Beta videotape -- (3 of 3) (Box-folder 19:3)
    - Captain Jim Lovell 12 December 2000, DVCam videotape (Box-folder 19:4)
    - Ken Starr 9 January 2001, Betacam SP videotape (Box-folder 19:5)
    - Ken Starr 9 January 2001, VHS videotape (Box-folder 19:6)
    - Ken Starr 9 January 2001, DVCam videotape (Box-folder 19:7)
- Photographs undated, 1997-2005
  This series contains photographs of various Norfolk Forum speakers and events.
  Chronological by the date of the event
  - John Major 15 October 1997 (Box-folder 20:1)
  - Dave Barry 7 April 1998 (Box-folder 20:2)
  - Elizabeth Dole October 1998 (Box-folder 20:3)
  - Dan Rather November 1998 (Box-folder 20:4)
  - Garry Trudeau February 1999 (Box-folder 21:1)
  - David Breshears May 1999 (Box-folder 21:2)
  - F. W. Deklerk October 1999 (Box-folder 21:3)
  - Capital Gang November 1999 (Box-folder 22:1)
  - Michael Bloomberg April 2000 (Box-folder 22:2)
  - Phillipe de Montebello May 2000 (Box-folder 23:1)
  - Walter Cronkite October 2000 (Box-folder 23:2)
  - James Lovell 12 December 2000 (Box-folder 24:1)
  - Ken Starr January 2001 (Box-folder 24:2)
  - Andrew Young May 2001 (Box-folder 24:3)
  - Madeleine Albright 29 October 2001 (Box-folder 25:1)
  - Stuart Varney November 2001 (Box-folder 25:2)
  - Judith Martin March 2002 (Box-folder 25:3)
  - Doris Kearns Goodwin May 2002 (Box-folder 25:4)
  - Ehad Barak October 2002 (Box-folder 26:1)
  - P.J. O'Rourke November 2002 (Box-folder 26:2)
  - Fred Thompson April 2003 (Box-folder 26:3)
  - Dr. Ballard undated (Box-folder 27:1)
  - Coach K September 2003 (Box-folder 27:2)
  - Robert Reich October 2003 (Box-folder 27:3)
  - Al Gore January 2004 (Box-folder 28:1)
  - J.C. Watts March 2004 (Box-folder 28:2)
  - Queen Noor June 2004 (Box-folder 28:3)
  - Tim Russert October 2004 (Box-folder 29:1)
  - Thomas Friedman January 2005 (Box-folder 29:2)
  - David McCollough April 2005 (Box-folder 29:3)
  - Box Contains Several Miscellaneous Loose Photos and Negatives undated (Box-folder 30:1)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize Photos are Located in Box 17, Folder 23. undated (Box-folder 30:2)